你是最弱一环
You are the weakest link.
这不仅仅是个游戏
This isn't just a game.
这里还有别的事情在发生
There's something else going on.
有选手离开了游戏
We have contestants outside the games.
游戏继续
The games continue.
这是五号卫星
This is Satellite Five.
一万个频道 都由这里播出
10, 000 channels, all beaming down from here.
我的主人 他们惧怕博士
My masters, they fear the Doctor.
告诉我 他们是谁
Tell me, who are they? !
我亲眼看见你死了的
I saw you die!
不可能 他们被摧毁了
That's impossible, they were destroyed.
显然他们幸存了下来
Obviously they survived.
我们抓到了你的同伴
We have your associate.
你不服从她就会被消灭
You will obey or she will be exterminated.
洛斯 -我在 博士
Rose? - Yes, Doctor?
我来找你了
I'm coming to get you.
神秘博士第一季第十三集
旅途终点
你认识博士
You know the Doctor.
你理解他 我命令你预测他的行为
You understand him. You will predict his actions.
我不知道 就算我知道 也不会告诉你
I don't know! Even if I did, I wouldn't tell you.
预测 预测 快预测
Predict! Predict! Predict!
检测到塔迪斯飞行中
Tardis detected in flight.
发射导弹 立即消灭
Launch missiles! Exterminate!
不行
You can't!
塔迪斯没有防御设施 你会杀了他的
The Tardis hasn't got any defences, you'll gonna kill him!
你的预测非常正确
You have predicted correctly.
有敌来犯
We got incoming!
推进器工作正常
The extrapolator's working,
防护力场充分发挥了作用
we've got a fully-functional force field.
这么绕口 喝醉的时候说说试试
Try saying that when you're drunk.
我的下一招
And for my next trick...
洛斯 蹲下
Rose, get down!
趴下 洛斯 -消灭
Get down, Rose! - Exterminate!
你成功了
You did it.
感觉就像和你分开好几年了
It feels like I haven't seen you in years!
我说过会来救你 -我也从没怀疑过你
I told you I'd come and get you. - I never doubted it.
我怀疑过 你还好吗 -挺好 你呢
I did. You all right? - Yeah, you?
还行 将就吧
Not bad, been better.
也给跟我抱一个呗
Hey, don't I get a hug?
来来来 -我在说他
Oh, come here! - I was talking to him.
欢迎回家 -我还以为再也见不到你了
Welcome home. - Oh... I thought I'd never see you again.
你运气好 我也只能开一枪
You were lucky, I was just a one-shot wonder.
这一枪耗尽了它所有的能量 现在它没用了
It drained the gun of its power supply, now it's just junk.
不要心急 我的同胞
Patience, my brethren...
你说他们灭绝了 为什么还活着
You said they were extinct. How comes they still alive?
本来他们是全宇宙最大的威胁
One minute they're the greatest threat in the universe,
突然一转眼就从时空中完全消失了
the next minute they vanished out of time and space.
他们是去打一场大战了
They went off to fight a bigger war.
时间大战
The Time War.
我还以为那只是传说 -我当时在战场上
I thought that was just a legend. - I was there,
戴立克和时间领主殊死搏杀
the war between the Daleks and the Time Lords,
决定的是全宇宙的命运
with the whole of creation at stake.
我的族人彻底灭绝 但也拉上了戴立克全族
My people were destroyed, but took the Daleks with them.
我曾以为这是值得的
I almost thought it was worth it,
现在看来他们白白牺牲了
and now it turns out they died for nothing.
外面有数千个戴立克
There's thousands of them now,
而我们连一个都抵挡不了
we could hardly stop one.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
反正在这闲聊说不死他们
No good stood round here chin-wagging.
人类啊 你们总是闲聊不止
Human Race, you'd gossip all day.
答案就在戴立克手里
The Daleks have got the answers,
我们去见见邻居吧 -你不能出去
let's go and meet the neighbours. - You can't go out there!
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
就这点本事
Is that it?
没用 零分
Useless! Nul points!
没事的 出来吧
It's all right, come on out,
防护力场可以挡住一切进攻 -几乎一切
that force field can hold back anything. - Almost anything.
没错 但没必要让他们知道的 谢谢
Yes, but I wasn't going to tell them that, thanks.
抱歉
Sorry.
你们知道在戴立克家乡
Do you know what they call me
流传的古老传说中是怎么称呼我的吗
in the ancient legends of the Dalek homeworld?
"即将来临的暴风雨"
The Oncoming Storm.
就算你们把所有情感都移除了
You might have removed all your emotions,
但我敢打赌 你们骨子里
but I reckon, right down deep in your DNA,
还是留了那么一丁点情感的
there's one little spark left.
那就是恐惧
And that's fear.
你们在我面前不觉得恐怖吗
Doesn't it just burn when you face me?
跟我说说
So tell me...
你们是怎么挺过时间大战的
how did you survive the Time War?
是我让他们存活的
They survived through me.
洛斯 上校
Rose, Captain...
这就是至尊戴立克
This is the Emperor of the Daleks.
你摧毁了我们 博士
You destroyed us, Doctor.
戴立克在你的怒火中毁灭
The Dalek race died in your inferno,
但我的飞船幸存了下来
but my ship survived,
在时间中飘荡 虽受损严重但还是挺过来了
falling through time, crippled but alive.
我明白 -不得插嘴
I get it. - Do not interrupt!
不许插嘴 不许插嘴
Do not interrupt! Do not interrupt!
我看你们忘了一件事 我是博士
I think you're forgetting something. I'm the Doctor,
我最擅长的事 就是说话了
and if there's one thing I can do, it's talk.
我会50亿种语言
I've got five billion languages
而你却一点阻止我的办法都没有
and you haven't got one way of stopping me,
所以要说有谁该闭嘴 那就是你们
so if anybody's gonna shut up, it's you!
很好 说到哪了
Okey-doke! So... where were we?
我们在黑暗虚空中等待着
We waited here in the dark space,
受损严重 但也逐渐恢复
damaged but rebuilding.
数百年过去
Centuries passed,
我们暗中入侵了地球的系统
and we quietly infiltrated the systems of Earth,
收集人类中间的废物
harvesting the waste of humanity.
囚犯 难民
The prisoners, the refugees,
无业者 都到了我们手里
the dispossessed, they all came to us.
他们被拆骨捣碎 细细过滤
The bodies were filleted, pulped, sifted.
人类已经被彻底扭曲
The seed of the human race is perverted.
只有十亿分之一的细胞适合加以培养
Only one cell in a billion was fit to be nurtured.
所以你用死人造出了一支戴立克大军
So you created an army of Daleks out of the dead.
也就是说 他们是半人类
That makes them... half human.
你的话简直是亵渎
Those words are blasphemy!
不得亵渎
Do not blaspheme!
不得亵渎 不得亵渎
Do not blaspheme! Do not blaspheme!
来自人类的一切都被彻底净化
Everything human has been purged.
我培养出了纯粹而神圣的戴立克
I cultivated pure and blessed Dalek.
戴立克什么时候懂得渎神这个概念了
Since when did the Daleks have a concept of blasphemy?
我在灰烬之中造出了新的生命
I reached into the dirt and made new life.
我就是戴立克之神
I am the god of all Daleks!
膜拜他吧
Worship him!
膜拜他 膜拜他
Worship him! Worship him!
他们疯了
They're insane.
在死一般的寂静中躲藏数百年
Hiding in silence for hundreds of years
足以把任何人逼疯了
that's enough to drive anyone mad,
但你比疯狂更恶劣
but it's worse than that.
被你自己的肉体逼疯
Driven mad by your own flesh...
被人类的污秽逼疯
The stink of humanity.
你们痛恨自己的存在
You hate your own existence.
这使你们比以往更加疯狂致命
And that makes them more deadly than ever.
我们要走了 -你休想逃走
We're going. - You may not leave my presence!
不许动
Stay where you are!
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
消灭
Exterminate!
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
消灭
Exterminate!
膜拜他 膜拜他
Worship him! Worship him!
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
把所有设备都打开 所有发射机
Turn everything up, all transmitters,
最大范围全速运转 快 -有什么效果
full power, wide open, now! Do it! - What does this do?
能防止戴立克直接传送登陆
Stops Daleks form transmatting on board.
你进行的怎么样了 你们联系地球了吗
How did you get on? Did you contact Earth?
我试着警告他们 但他们吊销了我们的许可
I tried to warn them, but all they did is suspended our licence
因为我们终止了节目播出
cos we stopped the programmes.
整个地球就这么干坐着坐以待毙
Then the planet's just sitting there defenceless.
琳达 你还在这里干什么
Lynda, what are you still doing on board?
我说过要你疏散所有人
I told you to evacuate everyone!
是她自己不肯走 -我不想抛下你
She wouldn't go. - I didn't wanna leave you.
再说穿梭机也不够了 否则我也走了
There weren't enough shuttles anyway or I wouldn't be here.
还有100个人被困在0层了
We've got 100 people stranded on Floor Zero.
听着 听着 我是罗德里克
Listen, listen, my name's Rodrick.
比赛我赢了 我的钱呢
I won the game, where's my money?
有人在听吗 我的钱在哪
Is anyone listening? Where's my money?
我的天呐 舰队开始调动了
Oh, my God, the Fleet is moving.
他们正在进发
They're on their way.
用烈焰净化地球
Purify the Earth with fire.
这个星球会成为我的神殿 我们将重新崛起
The planet will become my temple and we shall rise.
地球将成为我们的天堂
This will be our paradise.
戴立克的计划有个大漏洞
Dalek plan, big mistake,
因为他们给我留了一个东西
cos what have they left me with?
谁知道留了的什么吗
Anyone?
拜托 这是明摆着的
Oh, come on, it's obvious!
这个空间站是一个巨大的发射器
A great big transmitter, this station!
要是我能改变信号重组序列呢 有人明白吗
If I can change the signal, fold it back, sequence it? Anyone?
你开玩笑吧 -给你朵大红花
You gotta be kidding. - Give the man a medal!
δ射线
A delta wave?
δ射线 -什么是δ射线
A delta wave! - What's a delta wave?
是范·卡赛丹能量波 能把你的大脑烤熟
A wave of Van Cassadyne energy, it fries your brain.
一旦被它击中 你的脑子都会被烤糊
Stand in its way and your head gets barbecued!
这里可以传送超大能量波
And this place can transmit a massive wave,
消灭戴立克
wipe out the Daleks!
那我们快开始行动吧
Get started and do it, then!
可是要想建造出这么大规模的能量波
Trouble is, wave this size, building this big,
即使像我这样智慧的大脑也需要…三天
brain as clever as mine, should take... three days?
舰队还有多久才到 -22分钟
How long till the fleet arrive? - 22 minutes.
因为防护力场它们没法炸飞我们
We're now got a force field, they can't blast us out of the sky,
可这并不能阻止戴立克入侵
but that doesn't stop the Daleks from physically invading.
它们知道δ射线吗
Do they know about the delta wave?
它们几乎是和我们同时知道的
They've already worked it out at the same time.
如果它们想阻止博士
So, they wanna stop the Doctor,
这就意味着它们就必须到达第500层
that means they've got to get to this level 500.
我可以把外推器对准上面六层
I can concentrate the extrapolator on the top six levels,
从第500层到第495层
500 to 495,
这样它们就只能从下面进入空间站
so they'll penetrate the station below that,
从第494层登陆 一路打上去
at level 494, and fight their way up.
它们要和谁作战 -我们
Who are they fighting? - Us.
那我们拿什么作战
And what are we fighting with?
守卫们都拿着塑料子弹枪
The guards had guns with bastic bullets,
足够打飞戴立克了 -我们只有五个人
enough to blow a Dalek wide open. - There's five of us.
洛斯 过来帮我
Rose, you can help me,
我需要把这些电线的绝缘皮剥掉
I need all these wires stripping bare.
好吧 现在只有我们四个人了
Right, now there's four of us.
准备行动 上电梯 切断电梯的控制系统
Then let's move it! Into the lift, isolate the lift controls.
我只是想说 谢谢你
I-I just wanna say, um... thanks, I suppose.
而且我会尽力的
And I'll do my best.
我也是
Me too.
这很有意思
It's been fun.
不过我想应该没有下一次了
But I guess this is goodbye.
别这么说
Don't talk like that,
博士会成功的 你等着瞧吧
the Doctor's gonna do it, you just watch him.
洛斯
Rose. . .
你值得我为你而战
You are worth fighting for.
我希望我从来没有遇到过你 博士
I wish I'd never met you, Doctor.
我要一直是个懦夫就好了
I was much better off as a coward.
地狱里见
See you in hell.
他会没事的
He's gonna be all right.
对吧
Isn't he?
最后再问一次
One last time!
还有人愿意加入我们吗
Any more volunteers?
有一支军队就要入侵这个空间站了
There's an army about to invade this station.
我需要每一个人都加入防御
I need every last citizen to mount a defence.
别听他的
Don't listen to him!
根本就没有什么戴立克
There aren't any Daleks,
它们早在几千年前就消失了
they disappeared thousands of years ago!
谢谢
Thanks.
至于你们剩下的这些人
As for the rest of you,
戴立克会从第494层进入空间站
the Daleks will enter the station at Floor 494,
我只能告诉你们
and as far as I can tell,
它们会向上走 不会到下面去
they'll head up, not down.
可我也不能保证
But that's not a promise,
所以给你们几句忠告
so here's a few words of advice.
保持安静
Keep quiet.
如果你们听到上面传来打斗的声音
And if you hear fighting up above,
如果你们听到我们死了
if you hear us dying...
你们再来跟我说戴立克不存在
then tell me that the Daleks aren't real.
不要发出声音
Don't make a sound.
咱们走吧
Let's go.
假如
Suppose...
什么
What?
没什么
Nothing.
你刚才说"假如"什么
You said, "Suppose..."
没什么 我只是在想
No, I was just thinking...
我是说 虽然你不能这么做 可是
and I mean, obviously, you can't but...
你有一个时间机器
you've got a time machine.
为什么不能回到上周提前警告他们
Why not go back to last week and warn them?
从塔迪斯着陆的那一刻起
As soon as the Tardis lands, in that second,
我就被卷入了这次事件 困在时间线里了
I become part of events, stuck in the timeline.
我猜也是这样
Yeah, I thought it'd be something like that.
塔迪斯还可以做一件事 它可以带我们离开
There's another thing the Tardis could do. It could take us away.
我们可以离开
We could leave.
让历史顺其自然
Let history take its course.
我们去1989年的马贝拉
We go to Marbella in 1989.
是的 可是你绝对不会那么做
Yeah, but you'd never do that.
我是不会 但是你可以要求我
No, but you could ask.
根本没往那方面想 不是吗
It never even occurred to you, did it?
可能是因为我太好心了吧
Well... I'm just too good.
δ射线已经开始建造了 需要多久
The delta wave's started building. How long does it need?
情况很糟吗
Is that bad?
好吧 是有点糟 到底有多糟
OK, it's bad. How bad is it?
洛斯·泰勒 你真是个天才
Rose Tyler, you're a genius!
我有办法了
We can do it!
我可以用塔迪斯穿越我自己的时间线
If I use the Tardis to cross my own timeline. . .
没错
Yes!
把那个按下去 按住别动
Hold that down and keep position.
这是干什么的
What's it do?
消除缓冲 我真是太聪明了 不只是聪明
Cancels the buffers. If I'm very clever, more than clever,
我简直是天才 我要么可能拯救世界
and I'm I'm brilliant. I might just save the world
要么可能把它撕成两半
or rip it apart.
你还是拯救世界吧 -我也这么认为
I'd go for the first one. - Me too!
我需要给卫星再加点动力 你按住别动
I've just got to power up the Game Station, hold on!
博士 你在干什么
Doctor, what are you doing? !
我可以把手拿开了吗 它在动呢
Can I take my hand off? It's moving!
博士 让我出去
Doctor, let me out!
让我出去
Let me out!
博士 让我出去
Doctor, let me out!
一号紧急程序已启动
This is Emergency Programme One.
洛斯 听着 这很重要
Rose, now listen, this is important.
如果这则消息被激活 只可能意味着一件事
If this message has activated, then it can only mean one thing.
我们一定遇到了致命的危险
We must be in danger, and I mean fatal.
我已经死了 或者我已经失去了逃生的机会
I'm dead or about to die at any second
随时可能死去
with no chance of escape.
不要
No!
没关系的 希望我能死得痛快一点
And that's OK, hope it's a good death.
可是我答应过会照顾好你 我会做到
But I promised to look after you, and that's what I am doing.
塔迪斯会送你回家
so the Tardis is taking you home.
我不许你这么做
I won't let you!
我敢打赌 你现在一定又在大呼小叫
And I bet you're fussing and moaning now, typical!
但是请你听我说完
But hold on and just listen a bit more.
塔迪斯不可能再回来找我了
The Tardis can never return for me.
一号紧急程序意味着
Emergency Programme One means
绝不能让塔迪斯落在我的敌人手里
I'm facing an enemy that should never get this machine.
因此 你要做的就是
So this is what you do should do,
让塔迪斯死去
let the Tardis die.
让这个古老的盒子尘封起来
Just let this old box gather dust.
没有人能打开它 甚至没有人会注意到它
No-one can open it, no-one'll even notice it.
让它变成街角处一个奇怪的小东西
Let it become a strange little thing standing on a street corner.
经年之后 随着世界的发展
Over the years the world will move on
这个盒子会被深埋地下
and the box will be buried.
如果你想记住我 你可以做一件事
And if you want to remember me, then you can do one thing.
你只要做一件事就好了
That's all, one thing.
活得精彩
Have a good life.
就算是为了我 洛斯
Do that for me, Rose.
精彩地活下去
Have a fantastic life.
你不能这么对我 不能
You can't do this to me. You can't!
带我回去 带我回去
Take me back! Take me back!
不
No!
快飞啊
Come on, fly!
你怎么才能飞回去
How do you fly? !
帮帮我
Come on, help me!
我就知道
I knew it!
我在克利夫顿商业街那儿 听到了引擎的声音
I was all the way down Clifton Parade and I heard the engines.
我就想"只有一种东西会发出这种声音"
I thought, "There's only one thing that makes a noise like that."
怎么了
What is it?
洛斯 我调用了内部激光密码
Rose, I've called up the internal laser codes,
每一个屏幕上都应该有一个不同的数字
there should be a different number on every screen.
你能不能念给我听
Can you read them to me?
她不在 -什么时候上厕所不行
She's not here. - Of all times to take a leak?!
等她回来了 让她给我念一下密码
When she gets back, tell her to read me the codes.
她不会回来了 -什么意思 她去哪了
She's not coming back. - What do you mean? Where'd she go?
做你该做的事去吧
Just get on with your work.
你送她回家了 是吗 -是的
You took her home, didn't you? - Yeah.
δ射线能建造出来吗
The delta wave, is it ever gonna be ready?
告诉他真相吧 博士
Tell him the truth, Doctor.
δ射线当然有可能造出来
There is every possibility the delta wave could be complete,
不过你却无法改良它
but no possibility of refining it.
δ射线会杀死一切射程内的生物
The delta wave must kill every living thing in its path,
不管是人类还是戴立克
with no distinction between human and Dalek.
一切都会被你
All things will die
亲手杀死
by your hand.
博士 发射器的辐射范围将会覆盖整个地球
Doctor, the range of this transmitter covers the entire Earth.
你会将戴立克和人类一起消灭
You would destroy Daleks and humans together.
如果我是上帝
If I am God,
伟大的造世主
the creator of all things,
那你算什么 博士
then what does that make you, Doctor?
宇宙里还有人类的聚居地
There are colonies out there.
人类可以通过其他形式存活下去
The human race would survive in some shape or form,
可你们是仅存的戴立克了
but you're the only Daleks in existence.
如果我让你活着 整个宇宙都会陷入危险
The whole universe is in danger if I let you live.
你明白了吗 杰克
Do you see, Jack?
我做出这个决定是为了所有生命
That's the decision I've got to make for every living thing.
究竟是作为人而死去 还是变成戴立克活着
Die as a human or live as a Dalek.
你会怎么选
What would you do?
你把她送回家了
You sent her home.
她很安全
She's safe.
继续干 -但他会消灭你的
Keep working. - But he will exterminate you!
我从不曾怀疑他 以后也不会
Never doubted him, never will.
戴立克的神 现在你告诉我
Now you tell me, God of all Daleks,
有一件事我不理解 "恶狼"两个字
cos there's one thing I never worked out, the words "Bad Wolf"
传遍了时空的各个角落
spreaded across time and space, everywhere,
就为了吸引我的注意 你是怎么做到的
drawing me in, how did you manage that?
我什么也没有做
I did nothing.
得了吧 阁下 现在已经没有秘密了
Oh, come on, there's no secrets now, your worship.
那并不是我计划的一部分
They are not part of my design.
那是上帝的旨意
This is the Truth of God.
恶狼公司
这个地方越来越高端了
And it's gone upmarket, this place,
卖起了小盆卷心菜沙拉 不过不太好吃
they're doing little tubs of coleslaw now. It's not very nice.
有股消毒水味
It tastes a bit sort of clinical.
你去过明托路上那家新比萨店吗
Have you tried that new pizza place on Minto Road?
卖什么的 -比萨
What's it selling? - Pizza.
真不错 送外卖吗
That's nice. Do they deliver?
送的
Yeah.
洛斯 吃点什么吧
Oh, Rose, have something to eat.
二十万年之后
200,000 years in the future,
他正在死去 而我什么也做不了
he's dying, and there's nothing I can do.
就像你说的 二十万年以后 早着呢
Well, like you said, 200,000 years, it's way off.
不 那是正在发生的事情
But it's not, it's now.
那场大战正在进行 他在为我们而战
That fight is happening right now, and he's fighting for us,
为地球而战 而我还坐在这里吃薯条
for the whole planet, and I'm just sitting here, eating chips!
听我说 天晓得我有多恨那个人
Listen to me, God knows, I've hated that man,
但现在我爱他 你知道为什么吗
but right now I love him and do you know why?
因为他做了正确的事 他把你送回来了
Cos he did the right thing, he sent you back to me.
但是我每天都做些什么呢
But what do I do every day, Mum?
我都做些什么
What do I do?
起床 赶公交 上班 回家
Get up, catch the bus, go to work, come back home,
吃薯条 睡觉 就这样了吗
eat chips and go to bed, is that it? !
我们大家都这么过 -可我不能
That's what the rest of us do. - Well, I can't!
为什么 因为你比我们强吗
Why? Cos you're better than us?
我不是那个意思
No, I didn't mean that!
但那种生活确实更精彩
But it was. It was a better life.
我说的不是旅行
And I don't mean all the travelling and...
也不是外星人 飞船之类的
seeing aliens and spaceships and things,
那些不重要
that don't matter.
博士向我展示了一种更好的生活方式
The Doctor showed me a better way of living your life.
你应该很清楚 因为你也看到了
You know, he showed you, too,
他告诉你不要放弃 不要做旁观者
that you don't just give up, you don't just let things happen.
要顽强抵抗
You... make a stand,
要勇敢说不
you say no!
当众人作鸟兽散时
You have the guts to do what's right
要有勇气做正确的事 我做不到…
when everyone else just runs away, and I just can't...
琳达 现在你是我的耳目
Right, Lynda, you are my eyes and ears.
戴立克进来之后
When the Daleks get in,
你在屏幕上追踪他们 然后向我汇报
you could follow them on that screen and report it to me.
明白了 -他们会探测你的
Understood. - They'll detect you,
但是这扇氢化物做的门应该能挡住他们
but the door made of hydra combination should keep them out.
应该能
Should?
我也只能帮你到这儿了
It's the best I can do.
舰队什么时候到 -他们加速了
How long till the fleet arrives? - They've accelerated.
到时候了 各位 我们要上战场了
This is it, ladies and gentlemen, we are at war!
你不能仅凭对博士的怀念度过余生
You can't spend the rest of your life thinking about the Doctor.
但是我怎么能忘了他
But how do I forget him?
你得有自己的生活
You've got to start living your own life.
正常的生活 他从未有过的那种
You know, a proper life, the kind he's never had,
你要跟我一起正常地活着
the sort of life that you could have with me.
恶狼
这里 这里也有
Over here... It's over here as well!
很早就有了 不过是胡乱拼凑的短语
That's been there for years, it's just a phrase, just words.
我以为这是个警告
I thought it was a warning.
可能正好相反呢
Maybe it's the opposite.
这可能是一条信息
Maybe it's a message!
同样的单词 出现在二十万年之后和现在
The same words written down now and 200, 000 years in the future.
恶狼
这就是我和博士之间的联系
It's a link between me and the Doctor,
这里的恶狼 和那里的恶狼
Bad Wolf here, Bad Wolf there.
但如果这是一条信息 它想说什么呢
Yeah, but if it's a message, what's it saying?
它想说我可以回去 至少我能帮他逃脱
It's saying I can get back! The least I can do is help him escape!
大家要坚守阵地
Stand your ground, everyone,
听我指挥 祝你们好运
follow my commands and good luck.
你说对了
You were right,
他们强行打开了494层气密舱
they're forcing the airlock on 494.
现在只需让塔迪斯返航
All the Tardis needs to do is make a return trip.
原路返回就行了
Just... reverse.
但我们还是做不到啊
But we still can't do it.
博士总是说塔迪斯有心灵感应
The Doctor always said the Tardis is telepathic.
它有生命 可以聆听
This thing is alive, it can listen.
它现在没有在听吧 -我们得进去
It's not listening now, is it? - We need to get inside it.
我上次看到你 还有那个斯利辛人
Last time I saw you, with the Slitheen,
塔迪斯中间的部分被打开了
this middle bit opened,
里面发出了光
and there was this light,
博士说那是塔迪斯之心
and the Doctor said it was the heart of the Tardis.
如果我们能打开它
If we can open it,
我就能跟它交流 告诉它做什么
I can make contact, I can tell it what to do.
洛斯 如果你回去的话 你会死的
Rose, if you go back, you're gonna die.
我必须冒这个险
That's a risk I've gotta take,
反正我在这里也没什么好留恋的
cos there's nothing left for me here.
真的没什么吗 -没有
Nothing? - No.
如果你这么想 我们把它打开吧
OK, if that's what you think... Let's get this thing open.
启动内部激光器
OK, activate internal lasers.
削他们
Slice them up!
防御系统已经下线
Defences have gone off-line.
戴立克可能已经进来了
The Daleks may have ridden along.
你骗我 子弹根本不管用
You lied to me! The bullets don't work!
快点
Faster!
快点呀
Come on!
它没有动
It's not moving!
先锋部队已经抵达495层
Advance guard have got to 495.
杰克 情况怎么样
Jack, how are we doing?
495号好啊 我喜欢
495 should be good, I like 495.
说明你的身份
Identify yourself!
你是最弱一环 再见
You are the weakest link, goodbye!
太棒了
Yes!
你是最弱一环
You are the weakest link!
再见
Goodbye...
进入下一层级
Proceed to next level.
它们顺着通风管道往上飞 不 等一下
They're flying up the ventilation shafts... No, wait a minute.
天呐 它们为什么在往下飞
Oh my God, why are they doing that? They're going down!
消灭
Exterminate!
消灭 消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
消灭
Exterminate!
消灭 -你不能这么做 你根本不存在
Exterminate! - You can't! You don't exist
这不公平 是我赢了 我该变得富有
It's not fair! I won the game! I should be rich!
赢家是我 你不能这么对我
I'm a winner, you can't do this to me!
消灭
Exterminate!
在0层… 它们杀了所有人
Floor Zero... They killed them all.
不会有用的 甜心 博士也知道的
It was never gonna work, sweet heart, and the Doctor knew that,
他只想你安全 -我不能放弃
he just wanted you to be safe. - I can't give up.
锁上门 然后离开
Lock the door. Walk away.
爸爸就不会放弃
Dad wouldn't give up.
他也不在这里呀
Well, he's not here, is he?
就算他在 他也会跟我说一样的话
And even if he was, he'd say the same.
不会的 他会让我竭尽全力
No, he wouldn't. He'd tell me to try anything.
只要能救博士 就要竭尽全力
If I could save the Doctor's life, try anything.
你怎么知道
Well, we're never gonna know.
我就是知道 因为我见过他
Well, I know. Cos I met him.
我见过爸爸
I met Dad.
别犯傻了
Don't be ridiculous.
博士带我回到了过去 我见到了爸爸
The Doctor took me back in time and I met Dad.
别说了 -你记得爸爸死的时候吗
Don't say that. - Remember when Dad died?
有人和他在一起…
There was someone with him...
一个女孩 一个金发女孩
A girl, a blonde girl.
她握着他的手
She held his hand.
你从远处看见她 妈妈 你看到她了
You saw her from a distance, Mum, you saw her!
想想吧
Think about it!
那是我 你看到我了
That was me, you saw me!
别说了 -这就是博士的伟大…
Stop it. - That's how good the Doctor...
别说了 别说了
Stop it! Just stop it!
琳达 地球怎么样 -舰队在降落
Lynda, what's happening on Earth? - The fleet's descending.
它们在轰炸所有大陆
They're bombing whole continents.
欧罗巴…
Europa...
太平洋 新美洲联盟
Pacifica, the New American Alliance.
澳大拉西亚就这么不见了
Australasia's just... gone.
简直完美
This is perfection.
我在地球上创造了天堂
I have created heaven on Earth.
第499层 我们是最后一道防线
Floor 499, we're the last defence.
瞄准戴立克的眼柄 子弹就应该有用了
The bullets should work if you aim for the Daleks' eyestalk.
我把力场加到最大值
I've got the force field at maximum,
这样戴立克的火力应该是最弱的
so Dalek firepower should be at its weakest.
我在这都是为你
I'm only here cos of you.
因为你我才加入这个项目
I joined the programme cos you were on it.
我是不是该说 等一切结束
Am I supposed to say, "When this is all over,
而我们还活着的话 出去喝一杯如何
if we're still alive, maybe we could go for a drink?"
那敢情好 -想得美
That'd be nice. - Yeah, well, tough.
我们一定有什么可以做的
There's gotta be something else we can do.
妈妈说得对
Mum was right.
或许我们应该锁上门 就此放手
Maybe we should lock the door and walk away.
我无法接受
I'm not having that.
我无法接受我们就这么放弃 不可以
I'm not having you just... just give up now, no way.
我们只是需要比汽车更强大的东西
We just need something stronger than my car,
某个大家伙 比如那个
Something bigger, something like that.
你们可以用到六点 抓紧时间
Right. You've only got this until six o'clock, so get on with it.
妈妈 这是你从哪里弄来的呀
Mom, where the hell did you get that?
是罗德里戈 他欠我个人情 别问了
Rodrigo, he owes me a favour, never mind why,
但是甜心 你对你爸爸的判断是对的
but you were right about your dad, sweetheart.
他有很多疯狂的想法
He was full of mad ideas,
他一定会这么做
and it's exactly what he would have done.
趁我改主意之前 抓紧干吧
Now get on with it before I change my mind.
开火
Open fire!
没用的
It's not working!
集中火力 眼柄在两点方向
Concentrate your fire! Eyestalk two o'clock!
视力受损 我看不到了
Eye vision is impaired! I cannot see!
我们成功了
We did it!
不要啊
No!
我有麻烦了
I've got a problem.
发现人类女性
Human female detected.
它们发现我了
They've found me.
琳达 你会没事的
You'll be alright, Lynda,
工作站的那一侧防得住陨石
that side of the station's reinforced against meteors.
希望如此
I hope so.
你也知道地球盛产豆腐渣工程
You know what they say about Earth workmanship.
只有我了
Last man standing!
天呐 博士 赶紧把那玩意儿弄好吧
For God's sake, Doctor, finish that thing and kill them!
磨好屠刀 消灭人类
Finish that thing and kill mankind.
加油 -使劲踩油门
Keep going! - Put your foot down!
快点 -再加把劲 米奇
Faster! - Give it some more, Mickey!
继续
Keep going!
加油 加油
Come on, come on!
继续 -再加把劲
Keep going! - Give it some more!
洛斯
Rose!
博士 你最多还有20秒
Doctor, you've got 20 seconds maximum!
消灭
Exterminate!
别废话了
I kinda figured that.
好了
It's ready!
你得好好想想
You really wanna think about this.
如果我激活了这个信号
Cos if I activate the signal,
所有生命都会死去
every living creature dies.
我是不朽的
I am immortal.
你想试试吗
Do you wanna put that to the test?
我想看着你变得和我一样
I want to see you become like me.
伟大的博士 伟大的屠杀者
Hail the Doctor, the Great Exterminator!
别逼我 -证明给我看啊 博士
I'll do it! - Then prove yourself, Doctor!
你到底是个懦夫 还是个屠夫
What are you? Coward or killer?
懦夫
Coward.
一直都是
Any day.
因为你的软弱 人类将被屠杀
Mankind will be harvested because of your weakness.
那我呢
And what about me?
我会成为你们的天使之一吗
Am I becoming one of your angels?
你是异教徒
You are the Heathen.
你会被消灭
You will be exterminated.
或许时候已经到了
Maybe it's time.
警戒 塔迪斯正在实体化
Alert! Tardis materialising!
你逃不掉的
You will not escape!
你都做了什么
What have you done?!
我看透了塔迪斯
I looked into the Tardis,
塔迪斯也看透了我
and the Tardis looked into me.
你看的是时间漩涡
You looked into the time vortex.
洛斯 不该有人看到时间漩涡的
Rose, no one's meant to see that.
天理不容
This is the Abomination!
消灭
Exterminate!
我就是恶狼
I am the Bad Wolf.
我创造了自己
I create myself.
恶狼公司
我取下这个词语
I take the words...
把它们散播到时空中
I scatter them in time and space.
恶狼公司
用这条信息把自己引到这里
A message to lead myself here.
洛斯 快停下 你必须立即停下
Rose, you've got to stop this, you've got to stop this now!
整个漩涡
You've got the entire vortex
在你脑中回旋 你会被摧毁的
running through your head, you're gonna burn!
我只想保护你
I want you safe.
我的博士
My Doctor...
我要从伪神手中将你拯救
protected from the false god.
你伤害不了我 我是不朽的
You cannot hurt me! I am immortal!
你很渺小
You are tiny.
我能看透所有时间和空间
I can see the whole of time and space,
我能看清你的每个原子 并将之分解
every single atom of your existence, and I divide them.
一切归于尘土
Everything must come to dust.
万物皆有终时
All things. Everything dies.
时间大战就此停止
The Time War ends.
我不会死的
I will not die!
我不能死
I cannot die!
洛斯 你做到了 快停手吧
Rose, you've done it, now stop.
快放手 -我怎么能就此放手
Just let go. - How can I let go of this?
我能起死回生
I bring life.
这是不对的 你无权掌控生死
But this is wrong! You can't control life and death!
我就是可以
But I can.
我能掌控日月
The sun and the moon,
我能操纵昼夜
the day and night.
但我为什么这么痛苦
But why do they hurt?
这种力量会害死你的 这是我的错
The power's gonna kill you, and it's my fault!
我能看到一切…
I can see everything...
现在的一切
All that is...
过去的一切
all that was...
未来的一切
all that ever could be.
这是我一直以来看到的东西呀
That's what I see, all the time.
这难道不会把你逼疯吗
And doesn't it drive you mad?
我的脑袋…
My head...
过来
Come here.
好痛
It's killing me.
我想你需要一个医生
I think you need a doctor.
怎么了
What happened?
你不记得了吗
Don't you remember?
我好像…听到了歌声
It's like... There was this singing.
是的 我唱了首歌 戴立克就吓跑了
That's right, I sang a song and the Daleks ran away!
我本来是在家里的
I was at home.
不对 我在塔迪斯里 然后
No, I wasn't. I was in the Tardis and...
出现了一道光
there was this light.
其他就什么都不记得了
I can't remember anything else.
洛斯·泰勒
Rose Tyler!
我本想带你去很多地方 比如巴塞罗那
I was gonna take you to so many places, Barcelona.
不是巴塞罗那城 是巴塞罗那星
Not the city Barcelona, the planet Barcelona,
你会喜欢的 很棒的地方
you'd love it, fantastic place!
那里有没鼻子的狗
They've got dogs with no noses!
这个笑话就算讲一整天
Imagine how many times a day ended up telling that joke
都还是这么好笑
and it's still funny!
为什么不去呢 -你可能会去
Then why can't we go? - Maybe you will,
我也可能会去 但不是以这种方式
and maybe I will, but not like this.
你在胡说些什么
You're not making sense.
我可能无法恢复正常了
I might never make sense again,
可能长出两个头 或者没头
I might have two heads or no head!
想想我没头的样子 别说掉头等于整容
Imagine me with no head, and don't say that's an improvement.
但是这个过程有点微妙
But it's a bit dodgy, this process.
你不知道自己最后会变成什么样
You never know what you'll end up with!
博士 -别过来
Doctor! - Stay away!
告诉我你怎么了
Tell me what's going on.
我吸收了时间漩涡的全部能量
I absorbed all the energy of the time vortex,
没人承受得了这个
and no one's meant to do that.
我的每个细胞都在死亡
Every cell in my body's dying.
你不能做些什么吗 -我正在做啊
Well, can't you do something? - Yeah, I'm doing it now!
时间领主有个小诡计
Time Lords have this little trick.
可以说是一种欺骗死神的方法吧
It's, er... sort of a way of cheating death.
只不过…
Except...
这意味着我会改变
it means I'm gonna change,
我再也见不到你了
and I'm not gonna see you again...
反正不是这样 不是这副老脸
Not like this, not with this daft old face.
在我走之前… -别这么说
And before I go... - Don't say that!
洛斯…
Rose...
在我走之前 我只想告诉你 你棒极了
before I go, I just wanna tell you, you were fantastic.
绝对棒极了
Absolutely fantastic!
而且你知道吗
And do you know what?
我也棒极了
So was I!
你好啊…
Hello! OK...
新牙齿 真诡异 刚说到哪了
New teeth, that's weird. So where was I?
对了 巴塞罗那
Oh, that's right! Barcelona!